<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pans Labyrinth</title>
    <description>Life isn&#39;t a rat race.
</description>
    <link>https://pannzh.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://pannzh.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2015 20:10:26 +0800</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2015 20:10:26 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>If ——</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;If you can keep your head when all about you&lt;br /&gt;
 Are losing theirs and blaming it on you,&lt;br /&gt;
If you can trust yourself when all men doubt you,&lt;br /&gt;
  But make allowance for their doubting too;&lt;br /&gt;
If you can wait and not be tired by waiting,&lt;br /&gt;
  Or being lied about, don’t deal in lies,&lt;br /&gt;
Or being hated, don’t give way to hating,&lt;br /&gt;
  And yet don’t look too good, nor talk too wise:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you can dream—and not make dreams your master;&lt;br /&gt;
  If you can think—and not make thoughts your aim;&lt;br /&gt;
If you can meet with Triumph and Disaster&lt;br /&gt;
  And treat those two impostors just the same;&lt;br /&gt;
If you can bear to hear the truth you’ve spoken&lt;br /&gt;
  Twisted by knaves to make a trap for fools,&lt;br /&gt;
Or watch the things you gave your life to, broken,&lt;br /&gt;
  And stoop and build ’em up with worn-out tools:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you can make one heap of all your winnings&lt;br /&gt;
  And risk it on one turn of pitch-and-toss,&lt;br /&gt;
And lose, and start again at your beginnings&lt;br /&gt;
  And never breathe a word about your loss;&lt;br /&gt;
If you can force your heart and nerve and sinew&lt;br /&gt;
  To serve your turn long after they are gone,&lt;br /&gt;
And so hold on when there is nothing in you&lt;br /&gt;
  Except the Will which says to them: “Hold on!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you can talk with crowds and keep your virtue,&lt;br /&gt;
  Or walk with Kings—nor lose the common touch,&lt;br /&gt;
If neither foes nor loving friends can hurt you,&lt;br /&gt;
  If all men count with you, but none too much;&lt;br /&gt;
If you can fill the unforgiving minute&lt;br /&gt;
  With sixty seconds’ worth of distance run,&lt;br /&gt;
Yours is the Earth and everything that’s in it,&lt;br /&gt;
 And—which is more—you’ll be a Man, my son.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 25 Oct 2015 06:15:52 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>https://pannzh.github.io/life/2015/10/25/If.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://pannzh.github.io/life/2015/10/25/If.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>life</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>分叉的分叉</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;每次看到有关穿越（时间旅行）题材的电影或小说，总感觉很厌烦，一来本身无法自圆其说，二来也无法解释一些常见的矛盾如”祖父悖论”。
前几天又看了一部此类型的电影——《X战警逆转未来》，影片本身平平常常，但是由此衍生出现在的这些废话，亦即关于时间穿越的我的一些
想法和可能的解释，权且作为无聊思考的记录，并没有严格的证明。事实上我大学量子力学的期末考试依靠作弊也才70出头，想要给出严格证
明也是不可能的。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;首先，如果时间旅行真的可能，必须使得现在已知的悖论得以解决。为此我将世界假定为当下流行的“平行世界模型”，即每一个时刻的世界
都是平行发生的，当我碰到红灯时，有两种选择，一是继续前进，二是等待绿灯；继续前进的我是一个世界的我，姑且称之为世界1；等待绿
灯的我是另一个世界的我，称之为世界2；；两个世界各自平行地向前生长。在世界1里，也许我被车撞倒，进了医院；在世界2里，我通过马路，
正常打卡上班。这只是一种简单假设，实际上由于万物可以无限细分，选择也可以在无限的时间细分，大千世界里又有大千世界，毫不含糊。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;为了使问题简单，首先做一点简化。假设W为某一时刻的世界，并且在此时刻之后仅有两种发展的可能，即世界W1和W2，而后者也分别有两种
后续发展W11、W12、W21、W22。假设我们现在所在的世界为W22，并且打算穿越到W以改变当下的境遇（即逆转未来），那么过程应该如何呢？
穿越的方式有两种，一种为肉体穿越，即整个人连同内衣裤都转移到从前；另一种为意志穿越，或者说精神穿越，即尽有类似于灵魂的东西出
现在过去来改变世界运转。肉体穿越不大现实，所以暂且假定为意志穿越，即我现在的意志像灵魂出窍一样回到过去，并且附身于从前（W）的
自己，W的我的灵魂则压入堆栈，暂时失去身体的控制权，由此我就能开始改变世界啦！改变之后，W的灵魂W22出栈，回到W22中，享受修改了的世界。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;就这么简单了？刚刚说到世界像分叉一样向前生长，改变了的W是否还会生长到W2进而到我原来意识中的一模一样的W22呢？也许不会，但是
如果没有在穿越的时候大搞破坏的话，应该大同小异。也许回到W22之后会发现有些事变了，生命中会莫名其妙地少了几个人或者多了几个人。
X战警中就是这样的设定，但这是有问题的。原W22的金刚狼灵魂出窍修改了W再回到W22，但回去的W22（暂且成为W22B）已经不是原来的W22（称为W22A）了，
W22A的金刚狼的灵魂强占了W22B的金刚狼的灵魂，那么W22B的金刚狼的灵魂则在那一刻之后永远沉入栈底，这是多么可悲的啊，按照这种理论，还会发现他
在一夜之间性情大变，不觉得奇怪吗？&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;因此按照平行世界的理论，虽然穿越到过去可以实现，但是也无法改变现在。假设灵魂可以出窍，那么之后他将看到无数可选的世界（处于不同的时间），
改变过去之后会出现一个更好的现在，但是已经有原生的灵魂居住了。事实上根本不用去修改过去，就会有一个和现在类似的但是更美好的世界，与我所
来的世界平行前进，但是幸福是我的，幸福也不是我的。这也解释了我心里的一个疑惑，即为什么未来的我不穿越回来把福利彩票的中奖号透露给我，
因为一则我是如此之多，他根本就无法选择，二则即便透露了，快乐也是我的，他什么也没有。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;即便这些方式能解释穿越之后引致的矛盾，此外也还有更加严峻的问题，比如在W22时间结点之后，人类掌握的时间旅行的技术，那么从这一时刻开始，
各种不安分的灵魂就会到处乱窜，从前朴素的灵魂就会不断被压入堆栈，这点又怎么解决呢？反证而言，甚至可能灵魂根本就无法进入过去的人的身体，
无法左右过去的世界，只能在一片苍茫中无形地飘荡。结果是所谓的穿越时间，最终还是沦为一场4D的iMaX原始纪录片观影旅行。&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 25 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>https://pannzh.github.io/life/2015/10/25/falling-apart.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://pannzh.github.io/life/2015/10/25/falling-apart.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>life</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Welcome to Jekyll!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;You’ll find this post in your &lt;code&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run &lt;code&gt;jekyll serve&lt;/code&gt;, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To add new posts, simply add a file in the &lt;code&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory that follows the convention &lt;code&gt;YYYY-MM-DD-name-of-post.ext&lt;/code&gt; and includes the necessary front matter. Take a look at the source for this post to get an idea about how it works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll also offers powerful support for code snippets:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;Hi, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;#{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;Tom&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;#=&amp;gt; prints &amp;#39;Hi, Tom&amp;#39; to STDOUT.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com&quot;&gt;Jekyll docs&lt;/a&gt; for more info on how to get the most out of Jekyll. File all bugs/feature requests at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll&quot;&gt;Jekyll’s GitHub repo&lt;/a&gt;. If you have questions, you can ask them on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll-help&quot;&gt;Jekyll’s dedicated Help repository&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 1970 06:15:52 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>https://pannzh.github.io/tech/1970/01/02/welcome-to-jekyll.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://pannzh.github.io/tech/1970/01/02/welcome-to-jekyll.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>tech</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
